<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hotfix on Ian&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://bigredmachine.github.io/tags/hotfix/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hotfix on Ian&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bigredmachine.github.io/tags/hotfix/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Session state and Xdb tracking no longer required for rendering personalisation</title>
      <link>https://bigredmachine.github.io/post/session-state-and-xdb-tracking-no-longer-required-for-rendering-personalisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bigredmachine.github.io/post/session-state-and-xdb-tracking-no-longer-required-for-rendering-personalisation/</guid>
      <description>Happy Valentine&amp;rsquo;s day    Background So for quite sometime in order to be able to personalise a rendering on Content Delivery you&amp;rsquo;ve had to turn on Xdb tracking, even if you don&amp;rsquo;t want to use Xdb. And by turning on Xdb Tracking, you have to turn on ASP.NET Session State, or it blows up.
 &amp;ldquo;Xdb.Tracking.Enabled&amp;rdquo; = true &amp;ldquo;Xdb.Endabled&amp;rdquo; = false ASP.NET Seession State - Enabled  Personalisation without Xdb?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sitecore Log4Net Lockup - Hotfix</title>
      <link>https://bigredmachine.github.io/post/sitecore-log4net-lock-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bigredmachine.github.io/post/sitecore-log4net-lock-up/</guid>
      <description>Sitecore Log4Net Lockup - Hotfix &amp;amp; Don&amp;rsquo;t Share Appenders This post is about a very rare elusive bug that caused the affected Sitecore instance to freeze up, as well not log anything which gave a clue what the problem was.
It was a combination of a bug in the Sitecore Log4Net code and additional Log4Net configuration that had been added (not OOTB) that caused Sitecore to lock up.
 If you haven&amp;rsquo;t seen this issue, where a Sitecore instance locks up and you needed to restart IIS/Server, you probably won&amp;rsquo;t need this hotfix, but hopefully will get this hotfix rolled into a future version of Sitecore, so you&amp;rsquo;ll get the benefit then of hopefully never seeing this bug.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
