<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Ian&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://bigredmachine.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Ian&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://bigredmachine.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sitecore 9 Index Slow Down - fix</title>
      <link>http://bigredmachine.github.io/post/sitecore-9-index-slow-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bigredmachine.github.io/post/sitecore-9-index-slow-down/</guid>
      <description>Following an upgrade to Sitecore 9.0 update 2, from Sitecore 8.2 update 6, spotted that index rebuilds of the default indexes Core, Web &amp;amp; Master were taking much longer than they were before.
Talking to rebuild these 3 index in parallel under 50 mins in Sitecore 8.2, now taking over 6 hours in Sitecore 9 (sometime 20 hours+), for ~1&amp;frasl;4 million items in each of the web and master databases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speeding up sitecore crawling</title>
      <link>http://bigredmachine.github.io/post/speeding-up-sitecore-crawling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bigredmachine.github.io/post/speeding-up-sitecore-crawling/</guid>
      <description>Recently I was looking at building a sitecore search domain index (See Domain vs God index), which had quite a few calculated fields. Lots of the calculated fields were based off similar information about the parent nodes of the current item. And for each calculated field I was performing the same look ups again and again per field on the item.
I thought there has got to be a way to improve this, and found a forum post back from 2015 of someone asking the same question, and with a response of someone else who had solved it for one of the projects they were working on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logic App, Azure Function, Get Tweets Sentiment and Aggregate into an email</title>
      <link>http://bigredmachine.github.io/post/logic-app-azure-function-twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 20:49:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bigredmachine.github.io/post/logic-app-azure-function-twitter/</guid>
      <description>Fun with logic apps, Azure functions and twitter While studying for the Microsoft 70-532 exam, I wanted to take a look at Azure functions &amp;amp; Logics apps.
Having gone through this example &amp;ldquo;Create a function that integrates with Azure Logic Apps&amp;rdquo;
It left me with some questions on how to improve it. E.g. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to receive an email per tweet.
So after some searching, I came across a new feature called batching &amp;ldquo;Send, receive, and batch process messages in logic apps&amp;rdquo; but even after the batch had been reached, each message in the batch would result in an individual email.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>updating to Visual Studio 2015 RC</title>
      <link>http://bigredmachine.github.io/post/updating-to-vs-rc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2015 16:18:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bigredmachine.github.io/post/updating-to-vs-rc/</guid>
      <description>Updating from VS2015 CTP6 to RC A number of changes have been made to names.
Watch this for further details:
Video: ASP.NET 5 Community Standup - Mar 10th, 2015 - The Big Rename
Key slides:
  If you install visual studio, the DNVM and DNX will be setup for you.
To install Visual Studio RC, first uninstall visual studio CTP 6.
If you aren&amp;rsquo;t installing visual studio, and want to use the command line to install .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>setting up Visual Studio 2015 CTP 6</title>
      <link>http://bigredmachine.github.io/post/setting-up-visual-studio-2015-ctp-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2015 11:28:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bigredmachine.github.io/post/setting-up-visual-studio-2015-ctp-6/</guid>
      <description>Goals  To setup Visual Studio 2015 to run an asp.net vNext website Rather than using an Azure pre-configured VM, I wanted to setup Visual Studio on my own hardware.  How to do it/What I learnt Reading the Release Notes
 NOTE: Visual Studio 2015 CTPs are for testing and feedback purposes only. This release is unsupported and are not intended for use on production computers, or to create production code.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>